Jamil Dhanani

jamil.dhanani@gmail.com • github.com/jamil • jamild.com

Introduction

Thanks for taking the time to look at my resume; you can check out some of the projects I've worked on at <u>github.com/Jamil</u>. I also occasionally write on *The Fundamental Set* about topics related to both programming and math, at <u>blog.jamild.com</u>.

Skills

3+ years	2 years	<1 year
Python, JavaScript, C++, C, Objective-C	Verilog, Haskell, LISP/Scheme	R, MATLAB, Node.js, Swift

Work Experience

Software Engineer Intern, iCloud - Apple - Cupertino - May 2016 - August 2016 (Future)

- iWork for iCloud team
- Languages and tools: Objective-C, JavaScript

Research Assistant - University of Toronto, ECE Department - Toronto - October 2015 - February 2016

- Individually developed supervised time-series machine learning models for a research group studying the effects of lack of sleep on drivers, as part of the communications group at the University of Toronto
- Identified a multivariate vector ARIMA model to predict driver behavior on the road, incorporating data from brain-computer interface systems, including EEG data
- Languages and tools: MATLAB, R

Software Engineer Intern – Intel, Programmable Solutions (formerly Altera) – San Jose – May 2014 – Sept 2015

- Member of the Quartus II GUI team; worked on both server- and client-side code to support the Altera Cloud infrastructure, a tool which allows customers to run their compilations on both private and public cloud servers.
- Developed a REST API which allows clients to upload their hardware designs and launch remote compilations, and worked on a C++ wrapper around libcurl to make easy HTTP requests.
- Languages and tools: Django/Python, JavaScript, C++, SQL, Mongo

iOS Developer, Individual - Toronto - 2008 - 2013

- Created several iOS applications, including *TotalGPS* and *Cirrus*, an app which delivers aviation weather (METARs) for a given airport and parses them to display the data from the specific METAR components.
- 25,000 app downloads (16,500 paid) since 2008
- Languages and tools: Objective-C, Swift, OpenGL ES, Cocoa

Education

University of Toronto - Computer Engineering - 2017 - 3.80 CGPA

Bachelor of Applied Science in Engineering: Major in Computer Engineering

- Academics: Top 10 in Computer Engineering; 4.00 Sessional GPA (3.80 Cumulative)
- Honours, Participation: Dean's List, recipient of President's Entrance Scholarship, Member of the University of Toronto Aeronautics Team (UTAT), Hacker Academy, and LGBTQase (LGBTQ and Allies in Science and Engineering)

Selected Projects

Vasco [C++] Machine Learning

- A small C++ project that started off as an article recommendation algorithm, which I developed into a small group of machine learning classes.
- Currently supports stochastic and batch gradient descent, as well as k-means clustering. Available at https://github.com/Jamil/Vasco/

PhotoNotes [Objective-C] iOS, Core Data, Dropbox API, Optical Character Recognition

• Developed an iOS application at the Yale Hackathon, which allows the user to take photographs of their coursework and notes, and share them with classmates using Dropbox. Available at github.com/Jamil/PhotoNotes